快来，伙计们，快! 每个人都有份！
Come on, folks, come on! There's enough for everybody!
王子有足够的钱分给每个人
The Prince has enough for everybody.
1925年 贝尔格莱德 南斯拉夫王国
1925. BELGRADE KINGDOM OF SCS
拿着，等等，你拿最大的，快来
Take it. Wait, you take the biggest. C'mon.
大家相信我，我在战场上见过
People, believe me. I've seen it on the battlefield,
- 我今天看到了，我们都是平等的 - 王子万岁！
- I see it today. We're all equal. - Long live the Prince!
- 我们的恩人万岁! - 万岁！
- Long live our benefactor! - Long live!
该死的白痴王子
Damn with the dickhead Prince. The good Lord
在上帝的眼中，我们都是平等的
is watching us from above. We're all equal in the eyes of God.
但在国王的眼里可不是这样
But not in the King's eyes.
说得好，朋友
That's a good one, my friend,
但是你知道，我的哥哥亚历克斯
But, you know, my brother Alex,
他不是个聪明人
he's not a very clever man.
他正在带领这个国家走向深渊
He is taking this country straight into an abyss.
后面跟着一群唯唯诺诺的人
And he's followed by an army of yes-men.
但是世事无常
But nothing lasts forever.
那些货色不是为您准备的，殿下
That's not for you, Your Highness.
你怎么知道？
And how would you know that?
我们这里有更好的东西，真正的宝石
We've got something better here, a real gem.
原封未动
Untouched.
宝石... 那我可得去看看
A gem... Well, we have to check that out.
你会是她的第一个
You'll be her first.
上周他冲进最高法院院长的办公室
Last week he stormed into the office of the court governor,
掏出他的小兄弟，在院长的桌子上撒尿
pulled out his thing, and pissed on his desk.
他疯了
He is mad.
国王不知道该拿他怎么办
The King doesn't know what to do with him.
我们必须马上解决
We need to sort it out. Immediately.
你不会逮捕他吧？
You're not gonna arrest him, are you?
逮捕他？
Arrest him?
不，那是你的工作，塔尼
No. You will do that, Tane.
1928年 托波尼卡 精神病院
1928. TOPONICA, Mental asylum, SERBIA
南斯拉夫王国
KINGDOM OF SERBS, CROATS, AND SLOVENES
殿下
Your Highness.
我们可以至少跳过一次用镇静作为开胃菜吗？
Can we skip the sedative-appetizer at least once?
这是为了您好，让你更快好转
It is for your own good, to get better.
巴尔干半岛的阴影 第一季 第四集
BLACK SUN EPISODE 4
好的
Yes,
yes,
我明白... 好吧
I understand... Okay.
不幸的是，我被告知
Unfortunately, I was informed
殿下不能接见你
that His Highness cannot receive you.
与首相的会晤比预期的时间要长
The meeting with the Prime Minister took longer than expected.
我相信陛下的事情很紧急
I am sure that the issue is urgent,
缺席无可厚非
and the absence of His Highness is justified.
我们不止一次帮了你们国王的大忙
We made big favours to your king, more than once...
当然，我们很感激
Of course, we are grateful
感谢你在铁路建设方面的大力协助
for your great assistance in building the railway,
还有建筑领域的帮助
and in general, in the field of architecture.
当然，还有芭蕾舞
And, of course, thank you for the ballet.
我是说另一种帮助
I meant another kind of help.
比方说，我们被看作是行动
Let's say, the actions for which we are regarded
作为雇佣军
as a mercenary army.
你知道别人如何看待我们吗？
Do you know how we are perceived by others?
作为一个国家，在其中,
As a state in which,
除了正规军，还有数千名武装的俄国士兵
besides the regular army, there are thousands of armed Russian soldiers.
太可怕了
That's horrible.
当然，这并不会让我们感到困扰
But that doesn't bother us, of course.
相反，我们感到自豪
On the contrary, we are proud
成为欧洲唯一一个
to be the only country in Europe
并没有解除你军队的武装
that didn't disarm your army.
因为我们把你当作我们的兄弟
Because we consider you our brothers.
我们的..
Our...
我们的财政资金已经用完了
Our financial funds are exhausted.
人们开始失去信心
People are starting to lose faith.
是的我明白是的
Yes, I understand, yes...
关于这个问题，我想请你帮个忙
I would like to ask you for some help regarding that issue.
你知道我一直很乐意帮忙
You know I was always willing to help.
但是已经没有钱了..
But there is no more money...
你有正当理由为你的... 比如说... 生意
You have a justification for your... let's say... business.
恐怕此时此刻..
I'm afraid, at this moment...
我们不能给你更多了
we can't offer you more.
请放心我们的政府,
And rest assured that our government,
还有国王本人,
and the King himself,
会坚定不移
will be firm and persistent
不承认苏联的立场
in their position not to recognise the Soviet Union.
我还能为你做什么，将军先生？
What else can I do for you, Mr. General?
我想见沃因 · 朱基奇
I would like to meet Voyin Djukich.
相信我，那个人必须去医院
Believe me, that man had to go to the hospital.
伤口变得..
The wound became...
- 被感染了-是的被感染了
- Infected. - Yes, infected.
- 有坏疽的迹象-一大早就喝酒？
- There were signs of gangrene. - Early morning drinker, huh?
Babich 医生在他被绑架前一分钟给他做了检查,
Dr. Babich examined him a minute before he was abducted,
他没有发现任何坏疽的痕迹
and he didn't find any traces of gangrene.
再给我来一杯
Bring me another one.
- 巴比奇?-是的
- Babich? - Yes.
- 你问他了吗?-他是病理学家
Did you ask him? He's pathologist.
他甚至不知道活体组织是什么样子
He doesn't even know how the living tissue looks like.
- 给我!-好的，对不起
- Give me that! - Okay, sorry.
你好久没见过病人了
You haven't seen a patient for ages.
成千上万的人死在牢房里，你却不在乎
Thousands are dying in the cells and you don't give a shit.
你不是第一个质疑我道德观的人
You're not the first to question my ethics.
甚至议会也讨论过这个问题
Even the parliament discussed it.
但你总是忘记一件事:
But you keep forgetting one thing:
只有我一个人，还有将近一千个囚犯
I'm alone, and there are almost a thousand prisoners.
你必须跟着我的人! 你检查过他,
And you have to come after my guy! You examined him,
然后带他去了医院，就在有人
then took him to the hospital, just when someone was about
- 把他从监狱里弄出来-求你了局长告诉他
- to sneak him out from jail. - Please, commissioner. Tell him.
我真的没时间跟你说这些就我而言,
I really don't have time for this. And as far as I am concerned,
我的良心是清白的
my conscience is clean.
- 你的良心是干净的?-是的
- Your conscience is clean? - Yes.
好吧，我让他盯着那个俄国人
Okay. Alright. I told him to keep an eye on the Russian.
沃兰赫尔将军在这里
General Vrangel was here. What would have happened
如果他听说那家伙在拘留所里死了? 真是丑闻！
if he had heard that the guy died in detention? A scandal!
是的，现在你有一个死了的俄罗斯人，这不是丑闻吗？
Yes. Now you have a dead Russian, which is not a scandal?
都结束了，明白吗? 他们现在有新问题了
It's over. Understand? They've got a new problem now.
我们也是，新老板接替了 Tatko
And we too. A new boss has replaced Tatko.
- 我知道，那个蒙克-你怎么知道？
- I know, that Monk guy. - How do you know?
我问过他的几个手下，那个和尚无事可做
I questioned some of his thugs. That Monk has nothing to do
和牧师的谋杀有关所以我不在乎他
with the murder of the priest, so I don't care about him.
请去 Yataghan 贫民窟，然后谨慎地尝试
Please, go to Yataghan slum, and try discretely.
- 他们想知道真相-我知道
- They want to find that out. - I know they are.
为了消除竞争，你有托米奇
To eliminate the competition. You have Tomich.
- 他和鸦片打交道-让他帮你解决吧
- He works with opium. - Let him solve that for you.
拜托，俄罗斯人就在我背后
Please, the Russians are on my back.
哦，伙计! 我理解你的政治立场
Oh, man! I understand your political position.
快点！
Come on!
请不要操我
Just don't fuck me, please.
想做什么就做什么，但是要去做！
Do as you want, but do it!
不要再背着我做事了
Don't do things behind my back anymore.
我不会的
I won't.
塔内会付钱给你的
Tane will pay you.
- 再给我一杯白兰地-该死！
- Give me another brandy. - Damn!
- 对不起，我不知道你在这里-你为什么要道歉？
- Sorry. I didn't know you're here. - Why are you apologizing?
这是我的房子，我们可以为所欲为
This is my house. We can do whatever we want.
我希望这不是我想的那样？
I hope this is not what I think it is?
你自己说过，我应该尽可能多地陪着他
You said it yourself that I should be with his as much as possible.
他真有魅力
He's so charming.
而且主要是清醒的，我们开吃吧
And mainly lucid. Let's eat.
爷爷，我真的不介意，但是以你现在的情况..
Grandpa, I really don't mind, but in your condition...
如果你不高兴我找到了一个女人,
If you're not happy that I found a woman,
你可以搬出去了，对我和你都好
you can move out. Good for me, good for you.
你为什么不结婚呢？
And why don't you get married?
你把一生都奉献给了工作
You've dedicated your life to work.
我从来没有见过一个有博士学位的警察
I've never seen a man with a PhD work as a gendarme.
一个督察，爷爷
An inspector, grandpa.
回大学去教那些傻瓜吧
Go back to the university and teach those other fools.
把你的博士学位带回大学,
Take your PhD back to the university,
教那些傻瓜跟警察合作
and teach those other fools to work with the police.
爷爷... 你知道我非常爱你,
Grandpa... You know I love you very much,
但是请别这样，如果我想成为一名医生，我会成为一名医生
but please stop it. If I wanted to be a doctor, I'd be a doctor.
我想成为一名督察
I wanted to become an inspector.
你不需要接受那么多的教育
You didn't need so much education for that.
早上好
Good morning.
早上好，我给你带了奶酪
Good morning. I brought you that cheese.
给我留着，我一小时后回来
Save it for me. I'll be back in an hour.
- 胡椒-是的
- Peppers. - Yes.
我会回来的，我有点事要办
I'll come back. I just have to run some errands.
- 马上给我-新鲜的西红柿
- Give them to me now. - Fresh tomatoes.
- 过来-你的前男友？
- Come over here. - Your ex, eh?
我们不是说好了你不再来了吗？
Haven't we agreed that you won't come here anymore?
我们还商量了别的事情你昨晚在哪里？
We agreed some other things too. Where were you last night?
- 听着，你的丈夫...-我的丈夫是我关心的
- Listen, your husband... - My husband is my concern.
- 我有重要的事情要做-是吗？
- I had important things to do. - Oh, really?
你的工作并没有阻止你和我上床
It's not like your job ever stopped you from fucking me.
我不在乎你或他！
I don't care about you or him!
我生命中的每一个男人都背叛了我！
Every single man in my life has betrayed me!
我想我们应该休息一下
I think we should take a break.
你们都是懦夫，包括你们！
You are all cowards. Including you!
下午好，赖斯教授你还记得我吗？
Good afternoon, Professor Reiss. Do you remember me?
斯坦科 · 普里蒂科斯奇,
Stanko Pletikosich,
”刀是最常见的凶杀凶器
"Knife as the Most Common Homicide Weapon
在南海王国”
in the Kingdom of SCS."
警察学徒
Student apprentice in police.
多亏你的推荐，我现在是督察了
I'm an inspector now. Thanks to your recommendation.
他们把我转移到贝尔格莱德
They transferred me to Belgrade.
对贝尔格莱德好，对你不好
Good for Belgrade, bad for you.
对于贝尔格莱德来说，还没有定论
For Belgrade, the jury's out.
Pletikosich 先生，我相信你不是来聊天的
Mr. Pletikosich, I'm sure you're not here for small talk.
我看到了报纸
I saw the newspapers.
你是个幸运的人
You're a fortunate man.
有些人等了一辈子才得到这样一个有趣的病例
Some wait all their lives to get such an interesting case.
我不介意再等一会儿
I wouldn't mind waiting a bit longer.
- 我们面对的是个怪物-也许吧但是..
- We're dealing with a monster here. - Maybe, maybe. But...
杀人犯想要隐藏他们的行为,
Murderers want to hide their acts,
但是这一个把头砍下来，留给人们看
But this one cuts the head off and leaves it to be seen.
他要么是在炫耀，要么是在传递信息
He's either showing off, or sending a message.
什么信息? 说他疯了？
What message? That he's crazy?
不，这可能是一种仪式
No, it might be a ritual.
我们需要你的帮助
We need your help.
那是不可能的
That's out of the question.
我受够了塞尔维亚警察
I'm done with the Serbian police.
你们塞尔维亚人只有在战争中才是好的
You Serbs are good only in war.
我怀疑你是否知道如何平静地生活
I doubt you know how to live in peace.
教授..
Professor...
- 请再问一个问题-好的，但只有一个
- One more question, please. - Yes. But one.
这是第一个受害者的项链,
This is the necklace of the first victim,
这是画家的画布
and this is the canvas of the painter
认识第一个和第二个受害者的人
who knew the first and the second victim.
你可以看到鱼的符号，这里，还有这里
You can see the symbols of fish. Here. And here.
伊克提斯-伊克提奥斯，使徒是谁？
Ichthys-ichthios. Who were the apostles?
渔民
Fishermen.
没错，鱼是基督徒的象征
That's right; a fish is the symbol of Christians.
在罗马帝国的大流亡时期,
During the great exiles in the Roman Empire,
他们不被允许使用十字架,
they weren't allowed to use the cross,
所以他们把这个标志当作密码
so they took this sign as a secret code.
至于项链..
As for the necklace...
一个俄国人，沃兰赫尔的哥萨克人之一,
A Russian, one of Vrangel's Cossacks,
试图从他的情妇维奥莱塔 · 朱基奇那里偷走项链
tried to steal that necklace from his mistress, Violeta Djukich.
这就解释了罗曼诺夫家族的封印
That would explain the seal of the Romanovs.
- 我都没注意到-但凶手注意到了
- I didn't even notice it. - But the murderer did.
根据传说,
According to the legend,
俄国人把罗曼诺夫的财宝带到了贝尔格莱德
the Russians brought the treasure of Romanovs to Belgrade.
这样的东西值得为之杀人
And something like that is worth killing for.
教授，请收下这个
Professor, please keep this.
那么，我应该离开那个画家吗？
So, I should leave the painter?
这是你的调查，不是我的
It's your investigation, not mine.
做你认为你应该做的事，你不会犯错误
Do as you think you should, you won't make a mistake.
再见
Goodbye.
- 玛雅，你在这里干什么?-在我自己的工作室里？
- Maya, what are you doing here? - In my own studio?
我倒想问问其他人在哪里
I should rather ask where are all the others.
你不常来这里
Well, you don't come here too often.
我不知道
I don't.
如果你厌倦了艺术，我可以把这个工作室卖掉
If you are fed up with arts, I can sell this studio.
是的，但是那样的话你就得给我
Yes, but then you'll have to give me
你早就该给我的东西
what you should have given me a long time ago.
- 你以为我不会注意到?-我不明白
- You thought I wouldn't notice? - I don't get it.
玛雅，怎么回事？
Maya, what's going on?
Avram 别管这事
Avram, stay out of this.
这些不是我给你的底片
These are not the negatives I gave you.
是的
Yes, they are.
现在我想知道你是否背叛了我,
Now, I want to know if you cheated on me,
还是有人对你不忠？
or someone cheated on you?
无论哪种方式，你都必须让他们出现
Either way, you'll have to make them appear.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
求你了，再给我一点时间
Please, I need a little more time.
我没有，但我知道它们在哪里
I don't have them, but I know where they are.
很好
Nice.
今晚带他们去”尼什旅馆”
Bring them tonight to the "Nish Inn".
找裁缝
Ask for the Tailor.
如果你8点之前不出现，你就会永远消失
If you don't show up till 8. You'll disappear forever.
明白了吗？
Is that clear?
别紧张,
Take it easy,
那是我的画
that's my painting.
我不在乎
I don't give a damn.
嘿，画家..
Hey, painter...
告诉这个混蛋，没人敢动我的画！
Tell this scumbag that nobody messes with my paintings!
- 斯塔夫拉!-什么事，老板？
- Stavra! - Yes, boss?
你听到他说的了
You've heard the man.
别乱动他的画
Don't fuck around with his paintings.
我不会的
I won't.
很好! 放开他！
Good! Let him go!
看在上帝的份上，让他走吧！
Let him go, for Christ's sake!
下去
Go down.
下去，你这个人渣！
Go down, you scum!
很好，画家，你真有种
Good, painter. You've got some balls.
听着如果你厌倦了画画就给我打电话,
Listen, call me if you ever got tired of painting,
我需要一个会用刀的人
I need someone who's good with knives.
好的，小姐
Alright, Miss.
我希望现在你能更认真地对待我
I hope now you'll take me more seriously.
今晚到八点，否则..
Tonight until eight o'clock. Otherwise...
否则..
Otherwise...
别这样，别这样..
C'mon, cut that...
- 大家好-要白兰地吗？
- Hello, everyone. - Want some brandy?
据我所知，值班时不允许喝酒
As far as I know, it's not allowed to drink on duty.
菜鸟，要不是这杯白兰地，大家都会发疯的
Rookie, if it wasn't for this brandy everyone would go mad.
- Tanasiyevich 探长在哪儿?-谁知道? 被困在某个地方了
- Where is inspector Tanasiyevich? - Who knows? Stuck somewhere.
你查过”小木桶”了吗？
Did you check at "The Little Barrel"?
至于那个俄国人... 不用担心他
And as for your Russian guy... No need to worry about him.
圣彼得已经叫了他的名字，谢谢你，夫人
Saint Peter has called his name. Thank you, Madame.
干杯！
Cheers!
什么意思？
How do you mean?
他是在街上被枪杀的,
He was shot in the middle of the street,
可能是他自己干的最好别插手
probably by his own. It's better to stay out of it.
我们甚至不知道该拿自己的罪犯怎么办
We don't even know what to do with our own criminals.
- 你们真是一群白痴-你说什么？
- What a bunch of morons are you. - What did you say?
- 听我说，孩子...-听我说，警察
- Listen to me, kid... - You listen to me, copper.
我是探长先生
I am Inspector Sir for you.
如果你不好好称呼我，你就会被炒鱿鱼
And if you don't address me properly, you are going to get fired.
我说的够清楚了吗？
Am I making myself clear?
如果我没有我们可以和局长商量一下
If I'm not, we can sort this all out with the commissioner.
我想没有这个必要了探长先生
I think that won't be necessary, Mr. Inspector, Sir.
别喝了，别在这儿喝了
Cut that. And don't drink here anymore.
米利萨夫，跟我来
Milisav, come with me.
这是什么，如栅太太
What is this, Mrs. Ruzha.
我们生活的时代！
The times we live in!
别来无恙？
How's it going?
我被打了，至少他们治好了我的失眠症
I was beaten up. At least they cured my insomnia.
我睡得很熟
I slept like a log.
- Prsha!-是的
- Prsha! - Yes.
- 给他点止痛药-来了
- Give him something for the pain. - It's coming.
对不起，我不知道这里一团糟
Sorry. I didn't know it'd be a total mess.
我知道你没有但还是要谢谢你
I know you didn't. But thank you all the same.
我放了两天假
I got two days off.
你还记得他们长什么样吗？
Do you remember how they looked like?
我不记得我上过的女人和打过我的人
I don't memorize women I fuck and the people who beat me up.
但我觉得他们是俄国人，那家伙说俄语
But I think they were Russians. The guy spoke Russian.
给... 这种白兰地能创造奇迹
Here... This brandy does miracles.
还有给大家的小点心
And a little snack for the guys.
给我们一瓶
Give us a bottle.
- 是的-干杯
- Yes. - Cheers.
- 达维多维奇夫人...-塔纳西耶维奇督察在哪儿？
- Mrs. Davidovich... - Where is inspector Tanasiyevich?
- 他不在进来吧-我要见他
- He's not here, but come in. - I need to see him.
你可以告诉我，我们一起工作
You can tell me. We work together.
不，我不能，他在哪里？
No, I can't. Where is he?
我真的很想帮你，但是我有些生意上的事..
I'd really like to help you, but I have some business...
他在哪儿？
Where is he?
- 在”小木桶”里-谢谢
- In "Little Barrel". - Thanks.
但是如果你问我，我会说这里不适合女士
But if you ask me, it's not a place for a lady.
你在哪里看到一位女士？
Where do you see a lady?
这是给男士们的瓶子和辣椒
Here's the bottle and a chilly pepper for the guys.
我们喝完酒去拘留中心，走吧
Let's drink it up and go to detention centre. Come on.
我还没告诉你我有两天假呢
Haven't told you that I got two days off.
从他们那里
From them.
你这个邪恶的混蛋! 你以为你是谁? ！
You wicked bastard! Who do you think you are?!
- 别激动-够了够了安静！
- Take it easy. - Enough, enough! Quiet!
又一个前妻？
Another ex-wife, eh?
让这个傻瓜见鬼去吧! 看看她都干了些什么，塔宁！
To hell with the fool! Look what she has done, Tane!
冷静点，告诉我发生了什么事？
Calm down. Tell me what happened?
他差点杀了我我的家人朋友！
He could have killed me. My family, friends!
那天你换了包拿走了,
That day you switched and took from the purse,
你就是个警察! 你就是个小偷，这就是你！
Some policeman are you! You're a thief. That's what you are!
你为什么不告诉我你换了底片？
Why didn't you tell me you switched the negatives?
你为什么不告诉我他在追杀你？
Why didn't you tell me that he was after you?
我不确定
I wasn't sure.
我都不知道底片上有什么
I don't even know what's on those negatives.
你能描述一下跟在你后面的那个人吗？
Can you describe the man who came after you?
我可以
I can.
但我警告你，那个人很危险
But I'm warning you, that man is dangerous.
非常危险？
Very dangerous?
你的保护是没有用的，你的傻瓜甚至没有注意到
Your protection is useless. Your fools didn't even notice
他闯进了我的房子和工作室
when he broke in my house and studio.
你拿走了我的护照，我不能离开这个国家
You took my passport; I can't leave the country.
把底片还给我，马上！
Give me back the negatives. Right now!
我今晚必须把它们交出来
I have to hand them over tonight.
我有个更好的计划
I have a better plan.
来吧，萨沙... 告诉将军，别犹豫
Come on, Sasha... Tell the general, don't hesitate.
亲爱的将军，萨沙感到有点不舒服
Dear general, Sasha feels a bit uncomfortable.
如果你允许的话，我想告诉你他的请求
If you allow me, I'd like to tell you his plea.
Sasha 担心你会生气,
Sasha is afraid you might get offended,
但他不想去军官学校
but he doesn't want to go to the Officer School
感谢上帝你父亲没有听到这些
Thanks God your father didn't hear this.
他会第二次死去
He would die for the second time.
我最好的军官之一的儿子
The son of one of my best officers
不想去军校！
doesn't want to go to the Military School!
你父亲临死前我向他保证过我会照顾你
I gave your father my word before he died that I will take care of you.
你想做什么，萨沙？
And, what would you like to do, Sasha?
将军，我们很抱歉，这孩子还在哀悼..
General, we're sorry. The boy is still mourning...
他想和你在一起
He'd like to stay with you.
如果那孩子想这样,
Well, if that's what the boy wants,
不该是这样的
than that's how it should be.
那个人疯了！
That man has lost his mind!
我不得不亲吻他的手,
I had to kiss his hand,
把我们的父亲和兄弟送上西天的那只手！
the hand that sent our father and brothers to death!
萨沙，安静! 会有人听到的！
Sasha, hush! Someone might hear you!
即使这是真的，你为什么不给他一个机会赎罪呢？
Even if it's true, why don't you give him a chance to redeem himself?
我会给他一个机会
I will give him a chance.
那个人是谁？
Who is that man?
我在问你，那个人是谁？
Who is that man, I'm asking you!?
我不明白你在问什么
I don't understand what you are asking.
我上了她，然后她和一个商人结婚了
I shagged her and then she got married with some merchant.
她要是嫁给你一定是疯了
She'd be crazy to marry you.
我有东西要给你看
I've got something to show you.
不要习惯坐在我的办公桌前，明白了吗？
Don't get accustomed to sit at my desk. Is that clear?
巴比奇，去拿眼镜
Babich, get the glasses.
- 文件夹后面-是的
- Behind the folders. - Yes.
孩子，我听说你想和安提奇医生上床
Kiddo, I hear you want to screw Dr. Antich.
我不知道”上床”是什么意思但如果你想知道,
I'm not sure what the term "screw" means, but if you want to know,
如果我喜欢我的同事博雅纳,
if I'm fond of my colleague Boyana,
我可以告诉你，我邀请她共进晚餐，由女士来决定
I can tell you that I invited her for dinner and the lady will decide.
她会决定你是否要和她上床？
She'll decide if you're going to screw her?
不要那样说我们亲爱的同事
Don't talk like that about our dear colleague.
- 你好-请输入“ Rayatz”密码
- Hello. - Code "Rayatz", please.
- 是谁?-你在乎什么,
- Who is it? - What do you care,
我告诉过你密码了，帮我联系
I told you the code, just connect me.
哦拜托 Babich... 在那些文件夹后面
Oh, c'mon, Babich... Behind those folders.
- 你好-Djolovich..
- Hello. - Djolovich...
- 什么事?-我是塔尼
- Yes? - It's Tane.
- 你好吗，塔尼?-不错，伙计
- How are you, Tane? - Not bad, mate.
- 大声点-我要见你，马上
- Speak up. - I have to see you. Now.
来撒马尔罕吧
Come to Samarkand.
写下代码: “ Bradina”
Write down the code: "Bradina".
- Bradina-好的再见
- Bradina. - Okay, see you.
再见
See you.
该死的密码还有发明它们的人
Fucking codes and whoever invented them.
督察，我有些新发现
Inspector, I have some new findings.
关于什么? 做豆子？
About what? Making beans?
不，是调查
No, the investigation.
我在拜占庭看到了那些画家
I was in Byzantium and I saw those painters.
- 你他妈怎么回事?-我说我会询问目击者
What the fuck's wrong with you? I said I'd question the witnesses.
我只是个探长，只是骗你，我是出于尊重才照你说的做的,
I am an inspector just lie you. I did what you told me out of respect,
不是因为我不知道怎么做
not because I didn't know how to do it.
你只是警告他们把事情说清楚
You just warned them to get their stories straight.
还记得我们在那个俄国人身上找到的项链吗？
Look. Remember the necklace we found on the Russian guy?
是的
Yes.
我几乎可以肯定吊坠上鱼的标志
I'm almost certain that the symbol of the fish on the pendant
和这里的一样，我认为这里面有些东西
is the same as the one here. And I think there's something to it.
- 拜托我们逮捕 Avram 吧-我们为什么要逮捕他？
- Please, let's arrest Avram. - Why should we arrest him?
因为这不是原作? 因为他给她的项链上色？
Because it's not an original? Because he painted her necklace?
- 饶了我吧-这不是唯一的原因
- Give me a break. - That's not the only reason.
告诉你，孩子... 我受够了你的废话
Tell you what, kiddo... I'm tired of your bullshit.
这里有吃的吗？
Is there something to eat here?
我有一些奶酪，真的很好吃
I've got some cheese. Really good.
我就当你同意了，再见
I'll take that as a yes. Goodbye.
嘿! 你要去哪儿？
Hey! Where are you going?
上帝啊，真是个傻瓜，是个好小伙，但是个彻头彻尾的白痴
Sweet Jesus, what a fool. Nice lad, but a total moron.
- 随他去吧-干杯
- Let him be. - Cheers.
来吧，喝了这个，我们得走了
C'mon, let's drink this. We have to go.
- 探长，我是阿奇博尔德 · 赖斯医生-赖斯医生? 接过来
- Inspector, it's Dr. Archibald Reiss. - Doctor Reiss? Put him through.
莱斯医生为什么要报警？
How come Doctor Reiss is calling the police?
不知道
No idea.
- 我是阿奇博尔德 · 里斯-你好，医生
- Archibald Reiss speaking. - Hello, doctor.
我要和 Pletikosich 督察谈谈
I need to speak with Inspector Pletikosich.
他刚刚出去了
He just went out.
请给他留言，让他马上给我打电话！
Please, leave him a message to call me urgently!
- 我会告诉他的-好的
- I'll tell him. - Okay.
再见
Goodbye.
对不起，你能给我一些... ..
Excuse me, can you give me some....
- 零次获胜-太棒了！
- Zero wins. - Yes!
小心今天的女人，先生
Beware of women today, sir.
这里还有... 这里
Here and... Here.
- 零次获胜-太棒了！
- Zero wins. - Yes!
在赌博中如此幸运，爱情可能会让你付出很大代价
With such luck in gambling, love could cost you a lot.
这只是新手的运气和上帝的公正
It's just the beginner's luck and a bit of God's justice.
在哪里？
Where?
Bradina.
另一个警察
Another policeman.
你们这些安全部门的家伙过得不错
Nice life for you guys from the security service.
只是不要把密码告诉你的警察
Just don't spread out the code to your cops.
我不希望他们在这里
I don't want them here.
要不要来点香槟？
Would you like some champagne?
我不喝那个
I don't drink that.
调查进展如何？
How is the investigation going?
我想你比我更清楚
I guess you know better than I do.
- 我们不能创造奇迹-也许你不能,
- We can't do miracles. - Maybe you can't,
但是你的老板..
but your bosses...
日夫科维奇是不是决心要把他的爱好保密..
Is Zhivkovich so determined to keep his hobby a secret...
他有能力杀人吗？
that he is capable of killing?
- 你在说什么?-关于这个
- What are you talking about? - About this.
这他妈的是什么？
What the fuck is this!?
要我详细描述一下这个场景吗？
Shall I describe the scene in detail?
不要厚颜无耻
Don't be cheeky.
谁是幕后黑手？
Who is behind this?
我想知道拍这张照片的人的名字
I want the name of the person who took this picture.
他的名字叫内文，现在已经不在我们的管辖范围内了
His name was Neven and he is no longer in our jurisdiction.
- 底片在哪?-我明天去拿
- Where are the negatives? - I'll try to get them tomorrow.
我现在就要！
I want them now!
好吧，如果你现在想要，你就得自己去买
Well, if you want them now, you'll have to get them yourself.
明天10点钟到这儿来
Be here tomorrow at 10 o'clock.
所以日瓦科维奇与谋杀案无关
So, Zhivkovich has nothing to do with the murders.
这只是一个巧合
It was just a coincidence.
日夫科维奇什么都做得出来
Zhivkovich is capable of anything.
但在这种情况下，你错了
But in this case, you are wrong.
你的探员都不会杀我？
And none of your agents will kill me?
不，我向你保证
No, I guarantee you that.
我们都知道这个国家里有人
We both know that there are people in this country
没人能保护你
that no one can protect you from.
是的，塔宁
Yes, Tane. There are.
所以，注意你在做什么
So, watch out what you're doing.
- 我是以朋友的身份告诉你的-谢谢
- I'm telling you as a friend. - Thank you.
请从这边走
Please, go out this way.
我知道你有多谨慎
I see how cautious you are.
队长
Chief.
将军先生，很荣幸..
Mr. General, it is an honour...
下午好，朱基奇先生！
Good afternoon, Mr. Djukich!
- 进来坐下...-谢谢
- Come in, sit down... - Thank you.
求你了
Please.
对不起，我的俄语不太好
I am sorry, my Russian is not very good
当我听说你特别点名要我的时候，我真的很惊讶
I was really surprised when I heard you asked for me specifically.
我能为您做些什么？
How can I be of service?
首先请允许我表示我的哀悼
First allow me to express my condolences
为你失去妻子而感到悲痛
for the loss of your wife.
我很惭愧..
I'm ashamed...
我的一个手下参与了这个案子,
that one of my officers had been involved in this case,
如果他能被称为军官的话
if he can be called an officer.
但是现在我至少可以肯定十年的服务
But now I at least know for sure that ten years of service
对俄国沙皇军队的军官来说足够了
is enough for an officer of the Russian Tsar's Army
成为一个叛徒，杀人犯，小偷,
to become a traitor, murderer, thief,
还有奸夫！
and adulterer!
他让整个帝国军队蒙羞,
He disgraced the entire Imperial army,
为了这个..
and for that...
我深表歉意，朱基奇先生！
I deeply apologize, Mr. Djukich!
- 谢谢-他罪有应得
- Thank you. - He got what he deserved.
上帝之手惩罚了他
The hand of God punished him.
但他拿走了属于我的东西
But he took something that belonged to me.
不幸的是，他把它给了你妻子
Unfortunately, he gave it to your wife.
- 帕维里奇先生-等一下
- Mr. Pavelich. - Just a second.
很抱歉打断你，先生，你被捕了
I'm sorry to interrupt you, sir, but you are under arrest.
- 天啊! 这是什么? !-别这样医生
- Jesus! What is this?! - Don't be like that, doctor.
- 等媒体发现...-他们会很高兴发现的
- Wait till the press finds out... - They'll be happy to find out
一个国会议员如何打发他的闲暇时间
how a member of parliament spends his leisure time.
- 我有豁免权，退后!-别逼我扳倒你
- I have immunity. Back off! - Don't force me to take you down.
你想让我揍得你屁滚尿流吗？
Do you want me to kick the shit out of you?
冷静，把他带走！
Calm down. Take him away!
我应该穿些保暖的衣服
I should've worn some warmer clothes.
我们快到了，小姐
We're almost there, Miss.
我想我最好还是回家
I think it's best if I return home.
你不能回家，小姐，塔内叫我把你藏起来
You can't return home, Miss. Tane told me to hide you.
人渣在追杀你，他们没有心，没有灵魂
Scumbags are after you. They have no hearts, no souls.
他们只会打爆你的头
They just blow your head off.
米莉娅! 斯米洛卡！
Milya! Smiloyka!
小心点，小姐嘿，看我带谁来了！
Be careful, Miss. Hey, look whom I am bringing!
怎么回事? 你要带谁来我家？
What is going on? Whom are you bringing to my home?
- 你怎么了? 安静!-别安静！
- What is it with you? Hush! - Don't you hush me!
- 你在你那鬼地方找到她的?-她付不起账单
You found her in your hellhole? She couldn't pay the bill
现在你要把她带到我家来？
and now you are bringing her to my house?
看在上帝的份上，这是塔宁的同伴
For god sake, this is Tane's companion.
他派人来这里躲藏
He sent here to hide.
- 你为什么不早说?-我来介绍一下
- Why didn't you say so? - Let me introduce you.
这是玛雅小姐，这是我的妻子，斯米丽娅
This is Miss Maya, and this is my wife, Smilya.
我是斯米利亚
I'm Smilya.
- 玛雅，很高兴见到你-欢迎
- Maya, nice to meet you. - Welcome.
- 进来吧-这边
- Come on in. - This way.
你想喝点什么吗？
Would you like something to drink?
不可能！
No way!
但为什么呢？
But why?
好吧我确实给你带来了不好的运气,
Okay, I did bring you bad luck in gambling,
但我不想事情变成这样
but I didn't want it to be this way.
- 你们都是朋友-我看得出来
- You're among friends here. - I can tell.
这可能会有好结果
This can end well.
如果你认为这就是结局，那你就错了
If you think that this is how it ends, you're wrong.
不，这只是个开始
No, this is just the beginning.
虽然有点笨拙，但这是合作的开始
A bit clumsy, but it is a beginning of a cooperation.
我起诉你绑架的时候我们会在法庭上合作的
We will cooperate in court when I sue you for kidnapping.
告我绑架？
Sue me for kidnapping?
好吧
Alright.
但我认为这样做不明智
But I don't think it is a wise thing to do.
你找不到一个目击证人
You won't find a single witness.
你会丢脸的，放弃吧
You'll end up disgraced. Give it up.
我有个建议
I have a suggestion.
我们这里不是很喜欢你,
We are not very fond of you here,
- 但我们在很多问题上意见一致-比如... ？
- but we agree on many issues. - For example...?
例如，现任克罗地亚国会议员,
For example, that the current Croatian MP,
萝卜先生是一个精疲力尽的政客，他没有什么可以提供的
Mr. Radish, is a used up politician. He has nothing to offer.
不是对塞尔维亚人，也不是对克罗地亚人
Neither to Serbs, nor to Croats.
当然不是克罗地亚人，我不了解塞尔维亚人
Certainly not to Croats. I don't know about Serbs.
我们需要一个新的强有力的克罗地亚政治家..
We need a new and strong Croatian politician...
一个我们可以长期合作的人
Someone with whom we can have a long-term cooperation.
为了达成协议,
And to make that deal,
我们需要另一边来证明它已经准备好了
we need the other side to prove it is ready.
- 那是什么?-首先..
- And that would be? - Well, to begin with...
对 IMRO 案件的合理处理,
a reasonable approach to the case of IMRO,
你直接参与其中
where you are directly involved.
我想，一个合理的方法意味着我应该有所行动
A reasonable approach would, I suppose, mean that I should behave
- 作为第二个检察官，对吗?-不，拜托，我们不是孩子
- as a second prosecutor, right? - No, c'mon, we're not children.
我们希望这个案子结案，判个合适的刑期
We want this case closed, with an appropriate sentence.
细节就交给你了
I'd leave the details to you.
谁授权你提出这样的建议？
Who authorised you to make such a proposal?
我得到了最高层的授权
I have an authorisation from the very top.
哦，是的..
Oh, yes...
这是你的赌博赢家
Here's your gambling winning.
那么... 你打算怎么办？
So... What's it going to be?
所以... 我会考虑的
So... I'll think about it.
这是什么？
What is this?
- 你想和老板谈谈?-是的
- You wanted to speak to the boss? - I did.
你可以和他说话，但你不能见他
You may speak with him, but you may not see him.
这是什么鬼东西? 我不是你那个卑鄙的贝尔格莱德小偷
What kind of crap is this? I'm not your petty Belgrade thief.
凯罗，兄弟，你对我来说和其他人一样
Kyro, brother, you are the same to me as all of the others
想跟老板合作的人
who want to work with the boss.
同样的规则适用于每个人
Same rules apply to everyone.
你可以说话，但你看不见那个和尚,
You can speak, but you can't see the Monk,
要不要随你，兄弟，你想怎么样？
Take it or leave it, bro. What's it going to be?
阿夫拉姆 · 奈斯托维奇？
Avram Nestorovich?
不，是列奥纳多·达·芬奇
No, Leonardo da Vinci.
- Avram Nestorovic-你想要什么？
- Avram Nestorovic. - What do you want?
你因涉嫌谋杀 Violeta Djukich 被捕了
You're under arrest for the murder of Violeta Djukich.
- 你怎么敢? !-我们当然敢！
- How dare you?! - Of course we dare!
很长一段时间我都想抓住一个有钱的孩子
For a long time I wanted to bust some rich kid.
- Milisav 别管我的事-手
Milisav, stay out of my job. Hands.
我总是逮捕无赖..
I'm always arresting rascals...
所以你有点..
So you're kind of...
不许动! 我要开枪了！
Freeze! I'll shoot!
- 扔掉枪!-你扔掉刀！
- Throw the gun! - You throw the knife!
- 把枪扔掉!-别逼我开枪！
- Throw the gun! - Don't make me shoot you!
- 你要开枪?-你会杀了我的！
- You're going to shoot, eh? - You will kill me!
你以为杀一个人很容易? 得了吧！
You think it's easy to kill a man? Come on!
别这么做！
Don't do it!
去死吧！
Go to hell!
我再也不能画画了！
I'll never be able to paint again!
坐下
Sit down.
那是你的那个麻疯僧侣吗？
Is that Monk of yours leprous?
他为什么要躲起来？
Why does he hide?
督察，你是来逮捕这些无赖的吗？
Inspector, have you come to arrest these rascals?
放开我！
Let me go!!
这不是你第一次去酒馆吗？
This is not the first tavern you visited?
我需要一个裁缝
I need a Tailor
你错了，你不需要他
You're wrong. You don't need him.
不要..
Don't...
探长，有人了，我在等人
Inspector, it's occupied. I'm waiting for someone.
很高兴你知道我是谁
It's nice you know who I am.
我不认识你，但我知道你在等谁
I don't know you, but I know whom you're waiting for.
戴维维奇小姐派我来的
Miss Davidovich sent me.
疯女人！
Crazy woman!
- 她觉得我傻吗?-她派了个警察来
Does she think I'm stupid? She sends me a cop.
尼什基！
Nishky!
- 该死!-你的藤条有点酸
- Damn it! - Your vine got a bit sour.
当我从 Maudlin 买的时候就会发生这种情况
It happens when I buy it from Maudlin.
- 为什么，安特兄弟? 我是...-闭嘴，你这个笨蛋
- Why, brother Ante? I am... - Shut up, you fool.
条子你跑这么远就是为了炫耀,
Cop, did you travel this far just to show off,
还是你想从我这里得到什么？
or you need something from me?
听着，混蛋
Listen, bastard.
如果我放火烧了这个地方，你就完了
If I set this place on fire, you're done.
如果你放火烧了它,
If you set it on fire,
我要杀了你
I'll kill you.
如果我把这个给你，离戴维维奇小姐远点，好吗？
If I give this to you, stay away from Miss Davidovich. Okay?
警察，我上过更好的女人？
Cop, I've fucked better pussies?
把那个放下，去死吧
Put that down here and go to hell.
是你杀了摄影师吗？
Did you kill the photographer?
没有很抱歉我没有,
No. I'm sorry I didn't,
不过如果能安慰你的话我可以杀了你
but if it's any consolation, I can kill you.
你老板叫什么名字？
What's your boss' name?
不管我告诉你什么，你都不会知道我是否愚弄了你
Whatever I tell you, you won't know if I fooled you.
有道理
Fair enough.
告诉你的老板
Tell your boss
日瓦科维奇将军是个混蛋,
that Gen. Zhivkovich is a piece of shit,
但只有更大的人渣才会为此勒索他
but only a bigger scum would blackmail him for this.
你说得对，我老板是个大混蛋
You are right. My boss is a big jerk.
给拿着你想怎么样就怎么样
Here, take this. Do what you want.
我是凶杀案调查员我不负责敲诈勒索
I am a homicide inspector, I don't cover blackmailing.
离戴维维奇小姐远点
Stay away from Miss Davidovich.
如果有人受到伤害，而伤害又指向你，我就操你和你的老板
If somebody gets hurt and it points to you, I'll fuck you and your boss.
你真以为你能活着出去？
You really think you're getting out of here alive?
如果我不说你也不会说
Well, if I don't, neither will you.
炸弹! 伙计们! 他有炸弹! ! ！
A bomb! Folks! He's got a bomb!!!
走，把枪放下！
Move, put your gun down!
你从 Kaimakchalan 带了纪念品？
You brought a souvenir from Kaimakchalan?
你知道 Kaimakchalan 什么，你这个混蛋！
What do you know about Kaimakchalan, you scumbag!
你以为只有你一个人打过仗吗！
You think you were the only one who fought the war!
- 没有人为塞尔维亚流过血-你胆小鬼！
- Nobody else bled for Serbia. - You chickened!
我参战不是为了让某个醉醺醺的警察杀了我
I didn't fight the war so that some drunken cop would kill me.
他真的带了一件纪念品，我等了很久
He really did bring a souvenir. I waited a long time for this.
他总是这样接待别人吗？
Does he always receive people this way?
我是对的
I was right.
他的指纹出现在内文的相机上，还有维奥莱塔的服装上
His fingerprints are on Neven's camera, and on Violeta's costume.
我受够了
I'm fed up.
我不会像囚犯一样等他
I won't wait for him as a prisoner.
我来到贝尔格莱德就是为了受到这样的对待吗？
Did I come to Belgrade to be treated like this?
很高兴认识你，我是和尚
Pleased to meet you. I am the Monk.